Guide to the Emil J. Dillon Papers, ca. 1873-1933
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - Subseries 1. Letters, Telegrams, and Related Notes
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1ND of 5]1913 Sept. 28 - Oct. 1, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1NE of 5]1913 Oct. 7 - Oct. 23 / Nov. 5, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1NF of 5]1913 Nov. 13 - Dec. 16 / 29; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1OA of 5]1914 Feb. 1 / 14 - March 14 / 27, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1OB of 5]1914 Feb. 22 / March 7 - March 3 / 16, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1OC of 5]1914 March 5 / 18 - March 15 / 28; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1OD of 5]1914 August 20 - Oct. 13 / 26; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1PA of 5]1915 Jan. 11 - Dec. 25, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1PB of 5]1915 March 1 / 14 - March 3 / 16, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1PC of 5]1916 Feb. 28 / March 12, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1QA of 5]1916 Dec. 11 - 1917 April 27; n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1QB of 5]1918 April [?] 2 - 1919 May 18; n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RA of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RB of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RC of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RD of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RE of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RF of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RG of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RH of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [1RI of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2A of 5]1888 [?] August 21 - 1906 Sept. 22, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2B of 5]1906 Oct. 16 - 1907 August [?] 13, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2C of 5]1907 Sept. [?] 5 - 1910 Oct. [?] 29, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2D of 5]1910 August 25 - 1911 Sept. 20, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2E of 5]1912 Jan. 14 - 1913 Sept. 29, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2F of 5]1914 Sept. 8 - 1917 Jan. 20, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2G of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2H of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [2I of 5]n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [3A of 5]1906 [n.d.] - 1907 June 7 / 20, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [3B of 5]1907 June 8 / 21 - 1913 Sept. 28, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [3C of 5]1914 Feb. 1 / 14 - March 15 / 28; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [3D of 5]n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [3E of 5]n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [3F of 5]n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [4A of 5]1901 May 9, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [4B of 5]1904 Nov. 6 / 19; n.d. / n.y., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [4C of 5]1905 Feb. [n.d.], Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [4D of 5]1907 Jan. 18 / 31 - 1917 Nov. 28, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [4E of 5]1921 April 2 - April 3; n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [4F of 5]n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5A of 5]1914 [n.d.], Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5B of 5]1915, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5C of 5]1915 April [n.d.], Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5D of 5]1915 May - July [n.d.], Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5E of 5]1915 August - Sept. [n.d.], Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5F of 5]1915 Nov. - Dec. [n.d.], Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5G of 5]1923, Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count [5H of 5]n.d., Incl. descriptive lists, press cuttings, als, tls, typescripts, postcards, a photo, books, leaflets. (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Stishinskii, Alexander Semenovich1911 Feb. 4 - Feb. 14, Tls. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Contains materials in Russian relating to Iu. A. Ikskul', Baron.
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [1 of 16]1904 July 14 / 27 - 1905 Feb. 28; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Contains materials relating to Baron Rosen; Mr. George Harvey; Nicolas II; Mr. Roosevelt; Baron Komura; General Linievitch; Marshal Oyama; Mikado; Mr. Takahira; Rutkoffskii; Lamsdorff; Miss Fox; Mr. Sanderson; Mr. Wood. Some materials are in French, German, and Russian.
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [2 of 16]1905 Jan. 20 - July 17 / 30, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [3 of 16]1905 June 20 [?] - July 5; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [4 of 16]1905 July 20 / August 2 - August 29 / Sept. 11 [?], Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [5 of 16]1905 June 23 - August 18 [?], Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [6 of 16]1905 August 4 - 1908 [?] [n.d.]; n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [7 of 16]1905 August 6 - August 17, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [8A of 16]1905 August 7 - August 16, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [8B of 16]1905 August 18 - August 21, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [8C of 16]1905 August 22 - August 28, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [8D of 16]1905 August 29 - Sept. 19, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [9 of 16]1905 August 12 [?] - August 22, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [10A of 16]1905 July 16 - 1910 Dec. 31, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [10B of 16]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [11 of 16]1905 August 8 [?] - 1916 [n.d.], Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [12 of 16][n.y.] Sept. 7 - 1919 August 9, Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [13 of 16]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [14 of 16]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [15 of 16]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Treaty of Portsmouth [16 of 16]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, press cuttings, tls, typescripts, notebooks. (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Tsar [1 of 2]1896 Nov. 21, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 33, Folder 22)
      Contains materials in Russian relating to Nicolas II; Shishkin.
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Tsar [2 of 2]1896 Nov. 23, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Yalu Concession [1 of 2]1910 June 15 - June 20, Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a typescript. (Box 33, Folder 24)
      Contains materials relating to Nicolas II; Mr. W.L. Courtney; D.J. Fox; M.M. Bezobrazoff; Abazza; Van Larlarskii [Vonliarliarskii ?]; Alexeyeff; Peter the Great; Prince Lobanoff; Count Muravieff; Count Lamsdorff; Y.I. Briner; N.G. Matyunin; A.N. Kuropatkin; Count Vorontseff-Dashkoff; N.I. Neporoshneff; A.S. Yudenitch; A.I. Zveghintseff; Secretary of State Tikhonoff; Kishenskii; N. Seoyeff; S.N. Syromyatnikoff; Baron V.B. Freedericksz; Grand Duke Alexander Mikhailovitch.
    - Witte, Sergei Iulievich, Count - Yalu Concession [2 of 2]n.d., Incl. a descriptive list, tls, a typescript. (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Wooster, Mary1933 Jan. 30 (Box 33, Folder 26)
      Contains materials relating to Mr. Frank Wooster; Mrs. Dillon.
    - Wyman, H.H., C.S.P.1905 April 26 - 1939 Dec. 30, Incl. a descriptive list, a postcard. (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Yturbide, Eduardo N.1920 March 8, Tls. (Box 33, Folder 28)
      Contains materials in Spanish relating to Sr. Lic. D. Emilio Rabasa.
    - Zakrevski, J. [?]1904 June [?] 9 - June 20, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 33, Folder 29)
      Zakrevskii, J. [?]; Zakrewsky, J. [?]
    - Zografas, S.C.1914 June 10, Incl. a descriptive list. (Box 33, Folder 30)
      Zografos [?], S.C.
  - Subseries 2. Postcards
    - 1896-1901 (Box 34)
      Includes Austria (1899), Germany (1899), Asia and Far East (1900), Caucasus: Crimea, Georgia, Caspian (1900), Paris Exhibition (1900), Russian Types ()1900-1901.
    - 1902-1917 (Box 35)
    - 1917-1937 (Box 36)
      Includes: German Field Post & Pow (1917-1918); no date/a date is illegible; damaged; unposted...
    - Postcards, Viziting/Calling Cards (Box 37)
      Includes: unposted postcards; unposted Bulgarian postcards; unposted Mexico-Obregon campaign 1913-1920; unposted Soviet liders 1928; unposted panel greeting cards;viziting/calling cards arranged in alphabetical order and unidentified.
- Series 2. Correspondence, 3
  - Address Booksundated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chronology for Memoirs [1 of 5]1878 Feb. 5-1891 July 4; includes undated. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chronology for Memoirs [2 of 5]1891 Sept. 12-1894 Dec. 31; includes undated. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chronology for Memoirs [3 of 5]1895 June 10-1898 Oct.3; includes undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronology for Memoirs [4 of 5]1899 Jan.7-1902 Oct.6; includes undated. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chronology for Memoirs [5 of 5]1903 July 25-1910 Dec.22; includes undated. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence & Diary Notes [1 of 3]1874 March 2-1880[n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence & Diary Notes [2 of 3]1880 May 8- 1881 March 1/13 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence & Diary Notes [3 of 3]1881 Aug. 18/30-1885 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Journals1886-1890 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [1 of 35]1885 Dec. 29-1886 Feb.20[?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [2 of 35]1890 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [3 of 35]1892 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [4 of 35]1893 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [5a of 35]1897 Feb.11-1899 Feb.17 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [5b of 35]1897 April [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [6 of 35]1898[?] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [7a of 35]1900 Feb.1-May[n.d.]; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [7ba of 35]1900 [?]-1901 Sept.6[?] (Box 2.1, Folder 1)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [7bb of 35]1900 [?]-1901 Sept.6[?] (Box 2.1, Folder 2)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [7bc of 35]1900 [?]-1901 Sept.6[?] (Box 2.1, Folder 3)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [7c of 35]1900 [?]-1907[?] (Box 2.1, Folder 4)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [8 of 35]1902 (Box 2.1, Folder 5)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [9 of 35]1903 (Box 2.1, Folder 6)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [10a of 35]1905; includes undated materials (Box 2.1, Folder 7)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [10b of 35]1905 May[n.d.] (Box 2.1, Folder 8)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [11 of 35]1906 (Box 2.1, Folder 9)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [12a of 35]1907 (Box 2.1, Folder 10)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [12b of 35]1907 (Box 2.1, Folder 11)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [13a of 35]1904 April16/29-1908 (Box 2.1, Folder 12)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [13b of 35]1908 Feb.[n.d.]; includes undated materials (Box 2.1, Folder 13)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [14a of 35]1909 (Box 2.1, Folder 14)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [14b of 35]1909 (Box 2.1, Folder 15)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [15 of 35]1910 (Box 2.2, Folder 1)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [16 of 35]1912 (Box 2.2, Folder 2)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [17 of 35]1913 (Box 2.2, Folder 3)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [18a of 35]1914 (Box 2.2, Folder 4)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [18b of 35]1914 (Box 2.2, Folder 5)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [19 of 35]1915 (Box 2.2, Folder 6)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [20 of 35]1916 (Box 2.2, Folder 7)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [21 of 35]1917 (Box 2.2, Folder 8)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [22 of 35]1918 (Box 2.2, Folder 9)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [23 of 35]1919 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [24a of 35]1920 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [24b of 35]1920 Aug.11; includes undated materials (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [25 of 35]1921 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [26 of 35]1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [27 of 35]1924 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [28 of 35]1925 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [29 of 35]1926 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [30 of 35]1927 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [31 of 35]1928 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [32 of 35]1929 June-1930 Aug. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [33 of 35]1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [34 of 35]1932 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Diaries & Memoranda [35 of 35]undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Diary Extracts1909 May 11 - 1916 Jan. 27 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Financial & travel records [1 of 2]1885 June 1 - 1914 April; includes undated materials (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Financial & travel records [2 of 2]1914 March[n.d.]-1917 May 4; includes undated materials (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Journal, 1912 [1 of 11]"1912 Jan. 19 - Feb. 22 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Journal, 1912 [2 of 11]"1912 Feb. 24 - March 3/16 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Journal, 1912 [3 of 11]"1912 March 6/19 - March 8/21 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Journal, 1912 [4 of 11]"1912 March 9/22 - March 10/23 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Journal, 1912 [5 of 11]"1912 March 14/27 - March 16/29 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Journal, 1912 [6 of 11]"1912 March 18/31 - March 23/Apr. 5 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Journal, 1912 [7 of 11]"1912 March 25 /Apr.7 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Journal, 1912 [8 of 11]"1912 March 28/Apr.10 - Apr. 4/17 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Journal, 1912 [9 of 11]"1912 Apr. 6/19 - Apr. 7/20 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Journal, 1912 [10 of 11]"1912 Apr. 8/21 - Apr. 29 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Journal, 1912 [11 of 11]"1912 Apr. 18/May 1; includes undated materials (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous records [1 of 2] 1870[n.d.] - 1933 Jan.[n.d.]; includes undated materials (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous records [2 of 2] undated/no year (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Notebooks [1 of 3]undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks [2 of 3]undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Notebooks [3 of 3]undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Official correcpondence [1 of 4]1887 Jan. 7 - 1900 July 26 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Official correcpondence [2 of 4]1901 Sept. 12 - Nov. 3 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Official correcpondence [3 of 4]1906 May 15 - 1916 Feb. 2; includes undated materials (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Official correcpondence [4 of 4]1916 March 28 - 1932 Feb. 18; includes no year materials (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Photocopies of Autograph Books [1 of 2]1919 Dec. 13; includes undated materials (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photocopies of Autograph Books [2 of 2]1913 Feb. 27 - 1933 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Series 3. Subjects and Events, 9 linear ft.
  - Subseries 1. Subjects
    - Balls in Russia in old times1892 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Includes a press cuttimg. Note: in Russian.
    - Censorship [1 of 2]1893 Ju[ne/ly?] - 1916 Jan. 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      "Includes tls. 187 Piccadilly, W. St. Petersburg ""The Illustrated London News and Sketch Limited"", Milford lane, Strand, W.C. Refers to: Mr. Le Sage; Mr. George; The Serbian Premier Pashitch; Sir Edward Grey; the French War Minister General Roques; General Sarrail; Mr. Asquith. "
    - Censorship [2 of 2]1916 May 29 - 1917 Feb. 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Central American Union1894[?] June 22 - 1922 June 11[?] (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Press cuttins. Note: some materials are in Spanish.
    - Ecclesiastical Notes - Russian Sects [1 of 20]1890 Feb. 3 - 1903 May; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 5)
      "Includes: press cuttings, letters, notes, manuscripts, typescripts, a viziting card, poetic translation. Refers to: Avvakum; Job; Nikon; Mr. Gladstone; Solomon; St. Josaphat; P.W. Bunting; Prof. Bickell; Dr. Wetzstein; The Pope; Churikoff; Daria Smirnova. Note: some materials are in German, Russian, French, and Greek?]."
    - Ecclesiastical Notes - Russian Sects [2 of 20]1892 June 11; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ecclesiastical Notes - Russian Sects [3 of 20]1892 July 21 - 1894 April 30; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ecclesiastical Notes - Russian Sects [4 of 20]1893 May 7 - 1894 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ecclesiastical Notes - Russian Sects [5 of 20]1893 Sept. 17; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ecclesiastical Notes - Russian Sects [6 of 20]1894 March 16 - 1896 March 19; includes undated materials (Box 1, Folder 10)